for what is Russia
ради чего Россия
fighting for the sake of the Russian people in
воюет ради русский народ на на
Donbass so good, for example, the Russian
Донбассе так хорошо вот например русский
people lived in the city of Bakhmut 70,000 people
народ жил в городе бахмут 70.000 человек
yes These are the people of Donbass Well, let's say yes,
да Это народ Донбасса Ну допустим да ээ
Russia completely destroyed this city
Россия уничтожила полностью этот город
now no one lives there Zero how did
там теперь не живёт никто Ноль как этому
Russia help this Russian population of the city of Bakhmut we will
помогла Россия
build it
построим
anew
заново
Hello O Europe Let's
Привет О Европа Давай нормально
talk normally let's And I am from the city of
поговорим давай А я из города
Khmelnitsky Ukraine And where are you
Хмельницкий Украина А ты
from Rostov Russia Rostov the Great or
откуда Ростов Россия Ростов Великий или
on the Don on the Don understood Listen, as you
на Дону на Дону понял Слушай как ты
see, this War is going on Yes, for what is
видишь вот эта Война идёт Да ради чего
Russia fighting for the
Россия воюет
sake of the Russian people in
ради русский народ на
Donbass so good, for example, the Russian
Донбассе так хорошо вот например русский
people lived in the city of Bakhmut 70,000 people
народ жил в городе бахмут 70.000 человек
yes These are the people of
да Это народ
Donbass Well, let's say
Донбасса Ну допустим
yes, Russia completely destroyed this
да Россия уничтожила полностью этот
city now no one lives there Zero how did
город там теперь не живёт никто Ноль как
Russia help this Russian population of the city of Bakhmut they
помогла Россия
rebuilt Why did they destroy their
отстроили Зачем разрушили ихние
houses so that Ukrainian nationalists would not
дома чтоб украинские националисты не
terrorize the local population Yeah That is,
кошмарили местное население Ага То есть
I understood correctly so that Ukrainian
я правильно понял чтобы украинские
nationalists would not terrorize the population
националисты не кошмарили население
Bakhmut you
бахмута вы
destroyed all the houses in Bakhmut And now
уничтожили дома в бахмуте все И теперь
people from Bakhmut are crawling out to different
люди из бахмута как вылазят по разным
cities,
городам да
not that they are crawling out there, everything
не то чтобы как они там вылазят всё
will be fine Well, they are without apartments, no one gave them
будет хорошо Ну они без квартир им никто
new apartments Yes, we will find 70,000 where to
новые Да 70.000 мы найдём куда
put them, where 7,000 have not yet been distributed, even in
пристроить где 7000 до сих пор даже в
Mariupol, houses were given there There are
Мариуполе не раздавали дома там дали Там
100 people and everyone is still protesting
100 человек и всё до сих пор митингуют
Where is the promised
Где обещанное
housing, look Find a rally now in
жильё посмотри Найди сейчас митинг в
this Mariupol, what housing, look
этом в Мариуполе что жильё посмотри
literally a month ago there
буквально месяц назад
was No, well, maybe someone was protesting I was
был Не ну может кто-то митинговала я 2
in Mariupol 2 weeks ago Yeah, 300,000
недели назад в Мариуполе был Угу 300.000
people were left homeless there,
человек там осталось без
how many were built, Housing, that's how many
крова сколько построили Жиль вот сколько
apartments were built in
квартир построили в
Mariupol, watch the film called
Мариуполе посмотри фильм называется
Ukraine of the Abyss, a film not a film, how many
украи бездны фильм не фильм сколько
apartments were built Well, less, that's less than we
квартир Ну меньше те вот меньше чем
wanted, and 7,000 in Bakhmut, where will they be
хотелось а 7000 в бахмуте куда их
resettled And how many  shot
переселят А сколько расстреляла
Ukrainian I don't know shooting but here are 70,000
украинская не знаю стреля но вот 70.000
population of Bakhmut where are you
населения бахмута куда вы их
taking them And do you know that
Дели А ты знаешь что там в
people were buried in apartment courtyards I
многоквартирных дворах людей хоронили Я
know yes but look look until Russia
знаю да но смотри смотри пока Россия не
came to Bakhmut everything was calm there
пришла в бахмут там всё спокойно было
really wasn't a single casualty really
правда ни одного погибшего не было
Well look before Russia
правда Ну смотри до того как Россия
started its in Bakhmut there were zero casualties no
начала сво в бахмуте ноль погибших
one was shot for some reason Yes
никого никто не расстреливал почему-то
really And when Russia When Russia
правда А когда Россия Когда Россия
came look like Let's
пришла смотри походу Давай ещё раз
look again until the twenty-second year Muti not a
смотри до дцать второго года Мути ни
single casualty Russia comes that's all that's
одного погибшего приходит Россия вот и
all that's how they always
всё вот и всё вот так у них всегда
came to help the Russian people of Donbass And
пришли помочь русскому народу Донбасса И
what how did they help Bakhmut Yes people lived in
что как помогли бахмут Да жили люди в
Bakhmut normally went to work
бахмуте нормально ходили на работу
studied got married walked and then
учились женились гуляли и тут пришли
liberators came and freed them from their
освободители и освободили их от ихних
houses everything you won't have houses residents of
домов всё не будет у вас домов жители
Bakhmut Go into the world yourselves like subscribe
бахмут Идите сами по миру лайк подписка
comment
комент
let's have a normal conversation with people like that I don't
давай нормально пообщаемся с такими не
want to Let's try to have a normal
хочу Давай попробуем нормально
conversation Well let's try  Let me
пообщаться Ну давай попробуем Давай я
come from Rostov But I've been living
сам родом из Ростова Но живу уже 18 лет
in California for 18 years In 2 years it will be the
в Калифорнии через 2 года будет
twentieth damn not far from us yeah Well
двадцатого блин недалеко от нас да Ну
how relatively By Russian standards
как относительно По российским меркам
this is Rostov - this is Papa Yes And Volgograd
это Ростов - это Папа Да А Волгоград -
is sonny po And can I ask why
это сынок по А можно вопрос почему у
you have this hanging behind This is not the flag of the
тебя вот это сзади висит Это не это флаг
United States of a Great Power I am
Соединённых Штатов Великой державы я
now a citizen of the States Well why Look
сейчас гражданин Штатов Ну почему Смотри
I'm not ashamed to hang the flag of my country
мне не стыдно повесить флаг своей страны
And this is the richest country the world's
да и это богатейшая страна мировой
dominant Leader yeah Of course you're
господствующий Лидер да Конечно тебе
ashamed you're ashamed to hang your flag
стыдно тебе свой флаг стыдно весить
because Russia is nothing even in
вешать потому что Россия ничего даже в
Syria to some Barmaley
Сирии каким-то Бармалея
Russia lost to someone Well
проиграла Россия кому-то проиграла Ну ты
explain to me at least one thing where Russia Well
мне объясни хоть одно где Россия Ну
lost to Syria to men in slippers lost
проиграла Сирии мужикам в тапочках
in Ukraine lost received in
проиграла в Украине проиграла получила в
Kyiv in Kherson in the Kharkov region
Киеве в Херсоне в Харьковской области
now in the Kursk region lost part
теперь в курскую область потеряла часть
everything Well that's how Russia lost yeah And whose is the
всё Ну так то Россия проиграла да А чья
Kursk region now
сейчас Курская область
Look
Вот смотри мне
guys guys from Ukraine guys from
ребята ребята из Украины ребята из
Ukraine sent me a gift to
Украины прислали подарок мне в
California yeah the license plate was taken from a car in the
Калифорнию да номер снятый с машины
Kursk region yeah they took it from some  vs
Курской области да у каких-то забрали вс
No, there is no Kursk region now,
Нет уже тепер Курской области
okay, don't tell me, you've been here for 4 months already,
нету да ладно не рассказывай ба уже 4
in short, that's it, who needs you there, he
Короче всё да вообще Кому вы нужны там
takes and takes, but
забирает и забирает а
why? Well, okay, Ukraine is asking the whole
почему Ну ладно Украина просит у всего
world for help. Well, not Ukraine. But this
мира помощи Ну не Украина А вот этот
Zelensky. Zelensky. This one is everything to me, but
Зеленский Зеленский Вот этот мне всё но
yeah, look, I'll explain why. And Russia has no
да смотри я объясню почему а России ни у
one, no one, the point is not that
кого ну ни у кого не суть не в том что
they are asking. The point is that we, Americans, are
они просят Суть в том что мы американцы
giving Ukraine our missiles to attack
даём Украине свои ракеты для атаки по
Russian territory. Today, they destroyed
территории России вот сегодня разнесли в
Rostov Oblast in Taganrog, my native
Таганроге Ростов обла моей родной
Rostov Oblast,
Ростовской области
they destroyed it there, they didn't attack, they already destroyed
разнесли там не атаковали разнесли уже
yours. Yours has even already admitted that yours.
ваши у вас даже уже даже признало ваше
Yes, the Ministry that the strike was by
Да Министерство что удар был
American missiles, atam. No, that's right,
американскими ракетами атам Не ну это да
maybe they changed their tune there. No,
может они там переобулись Базара нет у
my mom and dad live in Rostov, they
меня мама и папа в Ростове живут
said that it flew over Taganrog. So,
говорили по таганрогу прилетело Так что
in Rostov, you could even hear it, so
у них в Ростове даже слышно
tact. Well, look, that's why we, America,
что такт Ну смотри поэтому мы Америка и
are a superpower because we want to
есть сверхдержава потому что мы хотим
bomb Russia with our missiles, and Russia
бомбим Россию своими ракетами а Россия
can do nothing to America, zero.
ничего не может сделать Америке ноль
zero why can't it Oh and what
зеро почему это не может О а что вы
can you do to America That's all we
можете сделать Америке Это всё что
want Well look you just don't
захотим Ну смотри вы просто ничего не
want anything No well you
хотите
know how can I answer you right away
Да нет ну знаешь как я тебе могу сразу
I'm an ordinary citizen I'm not a
ответить Я обычный гражданин Я не
president I'm not a minister I'm not someone like
президент я не министр я ну не кто-то
that
такой
but I don't really
но как бы я и полноценно и политику не
know politics there well and how do they decide in
знаю там ну и как они там решают
their own way But if someone goes against
по-своему Но если кто-то пойдёт против
Russia then they've already gone Kursk region the
России так уже пошли курскую область
Americans have already captured Kursk region
американцы курскую область уже захватили
Yes how did they capture They all
Да как Они захватили Они там все все
died there Well so they all went against
полегли Ну так пошли всё пошли против
Russia went against Russia they took
России пошли против России взяли
shelling Russian territory
обстреливают территорию России
shelling with American missiles you
обстреливают американскими ракетами
know Well do you know at least one
знае Ну знаешь Ты хоть одну
story where Russia has ever
историю что где Россия хоть раз
lost Yes I know the Russo-Japanese War
проиграла Да знаю русско-японская война
lost the first Chechen War lost the
проиграла первая чеченская проиграла
second Chechen War a
вторая чеченская
bunch of wars lost by Russia the
проиграла куча проигранных Россией
First World Russia
воин Первая Мировая Россия
lost tho Russia lost it
проиграла тхо Россия
only won wars when
проиграла выигрывала войны только когда
it was with others when it
она с другими когда она с европейскими
was in a coalition with the European powers that's all
державами была в коалиции вот и всё
okay I won't I I say I'm an ordinary
ладно я не буду я я говорю я обычный
citizen Well I know that Russia cannot be
гражданин Ну я знаю что Россию не
defeated So who is going to defeat
победить Так кто её собирается побеждать
it  destroy simply Why is it called
её уничтожают просто Почему и называется
Russia a
Россия это
power How much is your salary in Russia
держава Сколько у тебя зарплата в России
holding
держа
I am like an ordinary loader 60,000 600
Я как обычный грузчик 60.000 600
dollars well yes a
долларов ну да
superpower I don't know what 600
сверхдержава я не знаю какой 600
dollars 60,000
долларов 60.000
rubles yes I'm saying it's 600 Yes I agree It's
руб да я же говорю это 600 Да согласен
not 600 dollars it's 590 dollars
Это не 600 долларов это 590 долларов
less poured in by half a million where is it
меньше прилил на полумиллиона куда
now a dollar costs 100
это у нас сейчас доллар стоит 100
rubles more than 100 more than 100 That is you
руб больше 100 больше 100 То есть ты
get 590
получаешь 590
dollars what 500 What are you talking about 100 dollars
долларов какой 500 Ты что 100 долларов
is already 60 not 100 dollars 108 already or
это уже 60 не 100 долларов 108 уже или
110 a dollar costs 100 rubles here but I am in Yes at
110 доллар стоит у нас 100 руб но я в Да
the moment Okay look come on so
данный момен Хорошо смотри давай так что
that your Russia on the world stage can
что ваша Россия на мировой арене может
from Syria it was knocked out Yes from the Kursk region an
из Сирии её выбили Да из Курской области
ordinary worker what are you
выбили обычна работяга что ты мне сейчас
telling me this now Well
это говоришь
what's the difference
Ну какая разница
Troy will
Троя
win any war it will win And how will
победит любую войну она выиграет А чем
it win how will it win with
она будет побеждать чем будет
people You will go
людьми Ты пойдёшь
to fight of course And why didn't you go already that's why didn't you
воевать конечно А что не пошёл уже вот
go Kursk region to protect this e not
что не пошёл курскую область
peace there will be a world then you will go Well, they didn't call
будет мировая тогда пойдёшь
me They don't call me but you po I do
Да ну меня не призывали Меня не зовут а
n't
ти по Я не хочу а стоп то есть Так ты не
want but stop that is So you don't want Well, of course they don't call me Why
хочешь Ну конечно меня не призывают А
go as a volunteer Yeah, I got it that
зачем идти добровольцем Ага понял то
is you need the Motherland to give you a direct
есть тебе нужно чтобы тебе Родина прямо
invitation
приглашение
no when I myself will get up when I
дала нет когда я сам встану когда я
look if you will see how your
смотри если ты будешь видеть как твою
mother
маму
If you will see how your mother you
Если ты будешь видеть как твою маму тебе
need an invitation Yes so that mother mother so that she would
нужно приглашение Да чтоб мама мама чтоб
say son Protect me or you
сказала сыночек Защити меня или ты
pick up and beat the enemy
подбери и набьёт супостата
And what am I running how much How much do you weigh
А что бегу сколько Сколько ты весишь
kilograms sevo
килограмм сево
Probably it's with boots about the devil we don't have
Наверное это с ботинками об бес у нас
such a
нет такой прино
thing Hello Hello where are
дело Привет
you
Привет ты
from
откуда
Moscow region And what by the way do they say Moscow region
Подмосковье А что вот кстати говорят
I don't understand how it is so
Подмосковье я вот не понимаю как это так
no near Kiev near Berlin like near St.
вот нет под киёв под Берлине типа под
Petersburg only with Moscow they say so Moscow region
Петербурге только с Москвой так говорят
Why so well because that's what they
Подмосковье Почему так ну потому что так
say that is there is Moscow there is a
и говорится то есть есть Москва есть
region Moscow region Yes they don't say
область Московская область Да не говорят
Moscow  they say Moscow region and no, there is
Московско говорят Подмосковье и вот нет
no such word near Rostov there is such a word near the
под Ростов нет такого слова там под
Urals
ураль
Yeah, okay, if you are picking on it, its not
Да это ладно это если придираться не
just interesting where it came from, like I dont
просто интересно откуда это пошло типа
know, yeah, thats
знаю да это
how I understood it in the vernacular, yeah, thats
так по народному понял по народному Да
all they say And where did you come from, Moscow
все гово А сам откуда приехал Московскую
region, you werent born here your whole life
область не тут родился всю жизнь
Cool And you were born or did someone give birth to
Прикольно А сам родился или кто-то родил
you Okay, lets not talk like
тебя Ладно давай не будем
that about the war, basically Whats unclear to you Where are
обе так про войну в основном А что тебе
we heading, where are you
во Куда куда мы катимся куда вы
heading The cave age is understood here, its
катитесь Пещерный век понят тут
clear theres nothing to discuss even where are
понятно тут нечего обсуждать даже куда
you heading here Well, I think that we pay attention to the world
вы катись тут ну я думаю что мся к миру
Yeah, no, everything is built on favorable
Да нет ээ всё строится на выгодных
terms Well, the benefit is, lets
условиях Ну Выгода давайте так ээ
look at the Kursk region from the point of
рассмотрим курскую область с точки
view of favorable terms What is the benefit of
зрения выгодных условий В чём Выгода
Ukraine giving you the Kursk
Украины отдать вам курскую
region
область
Yeah, I dont know If you need the Kursk region,
Да не знаю Если вам нужна курскую
take it Well, thats what we do, yeah Well, everything, everything, everything, everything is
область забирайте Ну мы мы так и делаем
fair, everything is
да Ну всё всё всё всё всё честно всё
fair, Kursk Rostov Bryansk
честно Курская Ростовская Брянская
Belgorod
Белгородская
Voronezh Well, this needs to be done Why will you
Воронежская Ну это надо сделать Почему
give it to me for the sake of peace, whats important, regions
ради мира отдадите вам что важно области
or
или
peace No, this needs to be done, no Well,
мир Нет это это надо сделать не Ну вы
lets do it Thats how you  Russians need land
давайте Так вам россиянам нужно Земли
or
или
peace We need both land and peace You are strong
мир Нам нужен и земли и мир вы сильно
No, it won't work that way Look, Ukraine
Нет так не получится смотри Украина
clearly said yes there will be no peace until you
чётко сказала да мира не будет пока вы
give us the Rostov, Belgorod,
нам не отдадите ростовскую Белгородскую
Bryansk, Voronezh, Kursk regions and the
брянскую воронежскую курскую области и
Krasnodar region Yes, if you want to
Краснодарский край Да если хотите тогда
fight then fight kill your people
воевать воюйте убивайте своих людей
Let them die Yes If your people are
Пусть умираете да Если для вас ваши люди
not important to you oh what are some pieces of
не важны ой вам что какие-то кусочки
land more important to you for your people Well, that's it Okay So
Земли важнее за своих людей Ну всё О'кей
you don't want peace you see you don't
Значит вы не хотите мира видишь не
want it Yes, it wasn't originally a conversation
хотите да не изначально же был разговор
about peace, after all, they tried to agree
о мире все же пытались договориться
correctly Well, look, the world is us, we are Ukraine Well,
правильно Ну смотри мир мы мы Украина Да
how would you understand that it is not
ну как бы ты понимаешь что это не
Ukraine that is NATO that is setting conditions Yes,
Украина это НАТО выставляет условия Да
NATO conditions Yes, what should NATO be
условия НАТО Да что э НАТО должно
present in I said in
присутствовать в Я же сказал в поясе
such a belt yes Belgorod, Kursk, Bryansk,
таком да Белгородская Курская Брянская
Voronezh, Krasnodar region And so
Воронежская область Краснодар И так
on Give these regions under the protectorate of
дальше Дайте эти области под протекторат
Ukraine I understand well that is why there is a
Украины я понял ну поэтому поэтому и
conflict Well, that's it So, will you be
конфликт Ну всё да Так что
patient if you want peace you will want
будете терпите захотите мир захотите вы
me Turn off the sound No It was my
меня звук Выключите Нет Это у меня
microphone that was turned off now you can hear
микрофон был отключался сейчас слышно
me I can hear but speak  I can't hear myself
меня я слышу но говорите Я себя не слышу
wait Can you hear
подожди Сейчас слышишь
me now? The microphone switched on, I
ня меня переключился микрофончик что я
heard you, you can't
вас слышал вы меня не
hear me Well, look, if a NATO missile lands in the Moscow region And
слыша Ну смотри если тебе в Подмосковье
your daughter will die, you want it
погибнет твоя дочка тебе это хочется
Kursk region or
Курска область или
Daughter, so this is such a conversation, as if I do
Доченька так это такой разговор как бы я
n't accept it at all, by and large,
вообще Не приемлю пому по большому
look, war, war,
счёту смотри война война
war - this is the death of loved ones, yes, a
ре война - это смерти близких да Тебе
NATO missile may land in you And I will
может в натовская ракета прилететь Да и
die, well, do you think, do you think, I am
погибну хорошо ты думае ты думаешь я
speaking out for the death of loved ones, or am I,
выступая за смерть близких кого-то или
this is war, war does not
там я это война война не разбирает
understand, you don't know, yours, is it your loved one
понимаешь это не знает твоя это близкая
or not, it will land The only
или не тя она прилетит Единственный
way to stop is to give these
способ это остановить отдать вот эти
regions to NATO and
области НАТО и
all this, I don't decide, that's right I'm not
всё это не я не решаю правильно Я же не
saying who decides I'm saying how this can be
говорю кто решает Я говорю как это можно
stopped NATO,
остановить НАТО
NATO wants to protect itself And it
ре НАТО хочет обезопасить себя Да и она
wants to make this belt
хочет сделать вот этот пояс
demilitarized under the protectorate of
демилитаризованной под протекторатом
Ukraine and that's it I understand that you don't
Украины и всё Я понимаю что вы не
decide Well, you don't decide,
решаете Ну вот вы не решаете
missiles are flying at
ракеты летят на
you, this I completely agree with you
вас это Я с тобой полностью согласен
Absolutely So  what yes but but the circumstances
Абсолют Так что да но но обстоятельства
are such that neither you nor I
складываются таким образом что ни меня
are asked about it people
ни тебя об этом не спрашивают люди
just do it and everything is all right well
просто делают и всё всё правильно ну
I am satisfied with it yes that is
меня меня это устраивает да то есть
NATO's position then as long as Russians are
позиция НАТО потом что пока россияне вот
like you mouth is satisfied Well
такие как ты уст устраивает Да ну у нас
look at our circumstances Yes what uh
смотри обстоятельства такие Да что э от
nothing depends on you nothing
тебя ничего не зависит от тебя же ничего
depends on you everything absolutely nothing
не зависит всё абсолютно ничего не
depends The only thing that you can that
зависит Единственное что ты можешь что
I would advise you to take so
бы я тебе посоветовал взять так
little Yes what depends on you
чуть-чуть Да от тебя что зависит
for example you can take your child
например ты можешь взять своего ребёнка
and take him somewhere far away to Siberia far away
и увести куда-то далеко в Сибирь далеко
to Siberia somewhere far away from cities
в Сибирь где-то подальше от городов
that will not be subjected to
которые не будут подвергаться
bombing Well if if this is how
бомбардировка Ну если если так об будут
things will be Most likely I will
обстоять дела Скорее всего я так и
do so uh Look this needs to be done already
сделаю э Смотри это надо уже делать
because when everything goes to hell Can you
потому что когда все ламану Ты
imagine how many people there are in Moscow and the
представляешь сколько в Москве и в
Moscow region Yes when everyone
Московской области людей Да когда все
starts leaving Moscow at the first
начнут выезжать из Москвы при первых же
shelling there will be a crush on the roads
обстрелах это будет давка на дорогах
fantasy you understand this is fantasy Well
фантазии понимаешь это фантазии Ну
why fantasy when
почему фантазии когда 22 24 февраля
Kyiv was bombed on February 22-24 Yes people also started
бомбили Киев Да тоже люди начали
leaving there were really traffic jams Yes and
выезжать реально были пробки Да так и
here you have fantasies  look in the Kursk
тут у вас фантазии смотри в Курской
region in the Kursk region these were also
области в Курской области это тоже были
fantasies This is a fact that's why it was necessary to
фантази Это факт такой вот поэтому и
talk so that this would not happen
надо было разговаривать чтобы такого не
Who needed to
было Кому надо было
talk politicians well so let them
разговаривать политикам ну так Пусть они
talk And you Take the child leave
разговаривают А ты Бери ребёнка уезжай
better make a dugout somewhere in Siberia
лучше делай землянку где-то в Сибири
now now things are standing in such a
сейчас сейчас стоят обстоят дела таким
way that I don't need to go anywhere
образом что мне никуда не надо уезжать
Yes yes yes there in Kursk they also laughed they
Да да да вон в Курске тоже смеялись
said the situation is And now Dude in short
говорили обстоят А теперь Чувак короче
I'm looking for a dude who lost his number in the
ищу блин чувака кто номер потерял в
Kursk region not What do you mean laughing
Курской области не Что в смысле смея
with Well they laughed for example they said there my
с Ну смеялись например говорили там у
rockets don't fly my drones don't
меня ракеты не летают у меня дроны не
fly and now in short he Belgorod
летают а сейчас короче он Белгородский
grandfather one acquaintance is sitting in the
дед один знакомый есть сидит в
basement there are bombings in
подвале бомбёжки у них в
Belgorod yes yes he is sitting but he didn't laugh laughed laughed laughed Yes there's nothing funny
Белгороде да да сидит но он не смеялся
I know Non laughed I know
смешного нет Я знаю Нон смеялся зна
Why what's funny
Почему чтом смешного
here I say this Look The thing is that
тут такое говорю Смотри Дело в том что у
I have no complaints against you Russians you have
меня нет претензий к вам россиянам вы
n't decided anything since the times of Ancient
ничего не решаете ещё со времён Древнего
Rome was  the principle that a slave is not responsible
Рима был принцип чтобы раб не отвечает
for his master so therefore Well, to make
за своего хозяина так поэтому Ну к вам
some kind of claim to you if you do not
какую-то претензию говорить если вы не
influence anything if you without Well, that's what you
влияете ни на что если вы без Ну вот ты
say, that's actually That's a
так говоришь вот вот на самом деле Вот
very
это очень такая
infantile position absolutely Here you are
позиция инфантильная абсолютно Вот ты
sitting so comfortable so to speak Yes, you have a
сидишь такой комфортный так скажем Да ты
lot of so to speak
очень у тебя много так сказать
attributes like that well in terms of there are some kind of copters you
атрибутики такой ну в плане там коптеры
are engaged in some kind of
какие-то занимаешься какой-то
activity you are substituting Although most
деятельностью подставляешь Хотя скорее
likely it's just a background You are just there it's a
всего это просто фон Ты просто там
green background just
это Зелёный фон просто
lie Here
ложи
you are Show that Green background just
тыж Покажи что Зелёный фон просто
lift it up you will
поднимай
show everything not a green
покажешь всё не Зелёный
background Yes, that's what you are doing you are engaged in this
фон Да вот ты занимаешься ты занимаешься
activity yes Yes, we are engaged in this
этой деятельностью да Да занимаемся этой
activity that's how there are a lot of people like that in Russia also do the same
деятельностью вот таки в России людей
Yes, that's why it's all I I I am bringing closer I am bringing closer just like
Да поэтому это всё я я я приближают я
in Russia or No, you
приближают так же как и в России ли Нет
think there are such people like
думаешь таких думаешь таких идейных как
you in Russia no, look No, the thing is that
ты в России не нет смотри Нет дело в том
those in Russia They are intensifying the war
что те что в России Они усиливают войну
And I just look The thing is that Russia is an
А я как раз смотри Дело в том что Россия
aggressor country Whoever helps Russia
страна агрессор Кто помогает России тот
helps the war I am helping to stop the
помогает войне Я помогаю остановить
aggressor that is  I am helping to stop the
агрессора то есть Я помогаю остановить
war, it's the same as our grandfathers
войну это ж так же как Гитлера наши деды
helped to stop Hitler.
помогали остановить Гитлера Да
Why? Well, because in this
почему Ну потому что в этом в любом
case, in the
случае
first place, it did not start out of
есть это во-первых началось это не на
nowhere. Where did
пустом месте А на каком
it start? Yes, there is a conflict of interest. Yes,
месте это началось Да конфликт интересов
it started because Russia is
Да это началось о том что есть Россия
also not some country, you know,
тоже ни какая-то страна там знаешь
which will be like,
которая будет такая типа
look who? Let's wait. Who is to
смотреть кто Давай так подожди Кто
blame for the fact that now your daughter is not to
виноват в том что сейчас на твою доч не
blame, as no one is to blame, someone,
виноват как никто не виноват кто-то
someone made a decision to attack
кто-то ж принял решение нападать на
someone. There
кого-то
is a conflict of interest. There is an absolute
есть конфликт интересов есть абсолютно
understanding of
точно понимание
that. Look again, look again, there is a conflict.
того ещ раз ещё раз смотри конфликт наты
You are transferring it specifically to me, to my
переводишь конкретно на меня на мою
daughter, if I am again. Explain this
доч если меня ещё раз Об объясни такую
situation. Who is to blame. A conflict of interest.
ситуацию кто виноват конфликт интересов
There is a conflict. They do not attack anyone.
есть конфликт не нападает ни на кого
Specific people are attacking based on a specific
нападают конкретные люди по конкретному
decision. Then who is to blame for the fact that they were there from the
решению то кто виноват в том что они
beginning. What do you think? Thousands of
изначально был А что ты думаешь тысячи
people just stood up and died for
людей просто так встали и умирают за
nothing. I don't know. I asked who is to
просто так я не знаю я спросил кто
blame. There are always two sides. There are always two
виноват всегда две стороны всегда две
Rons. Why? Look. E. Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Роны Почему Смотри Е стоп стоп стоп стоп
If someone comes up to you on the street,
Если кто-то подходит на улице к тебе
takes your phone from you, and hits you. You are
забирает у тебя телефон и бьёт тебя Ты
also to
тоже
blame. Well, wait, this is a conflict.  conflict
виноват ну подожди это конфликт конфликт
conflict two sides
конфликт две стороны
No it's all very simplified And I
Нет это всё очень упрощённый А понял я
understood correctly that the Soviet Union was to
правильно понимаю что Советский Союз был
blame that Hitler attacked it
виноват что Гитлер напал на
no yes they are to blame You said with your
него нет да виноваты Ты же сказал своим
mouth that both sides are always to blame
ртом что виноваты всегда две
yes the Soviet Union was to blame
стороны да то Советский Союз был виноват
that Hitler attacked it absolutely that is to
в том что Гитлер на него напал абсолютно
say the Soviet Union is to blame for
то есть сове Советский Союз виноват в
unleashing the Second World War understood
развязывании Второй мировой войны понял
you know that in Russia what you are
ты знаешь что у вас в России то что ты
saying now is criminal
сейчас говоришь это криминальная
liability criminal liability
ответственность уголов ответственность
Well I will probably bear responsibility
Ну я наверное понесу э ответственность
if if I bear responsibility for this
если если я понесу за это
well And the question is yes
ответственность хорошо А вопрос да
Poland Poland Poland is to blame that
Польша Польша Польша виновата в том что
Hitler attacked
Гитлер напал на
Poland Poland you understand you
Польшу Польша ты понимаешь ты
are talking as if you are a country I am
разговариваешь как будто ты страна Я
asking you you said it is
тебя спрашиваю ты сказал виноваты
always to blame simply
всегда просто
Hello
Здравствуйте
Popik Hello Not
Попик Здравствуйте Не
Popik How are you I am from the city of
Попик Как ваши дела Я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you from Yes I know you all I
Хмельницке Вы откуда Да я знаю вас всё
know you Where are you from What difference does it make where I am from
вас знаю Вы откуда А какая разница
Well I am interested No well what
откуда я Ну мне интересно Не ну какая
difference does it make in principle well I am
вообще разница в принципе ну вот
interested because Well for example there
интересно потому что Ну вот например
are people from Moscow there are from Vladivostok
есть люди из Москвы есть с Владивостока
I analyze where more adequate
я анализирую откуда больше адекватные
where more
откуда больше
that is and how do you How do you generally
то есть а как вы Как вы вообще
understand it is very simple at  me for example
понимаете очень просто у меня например
yes here [ __ ] is very simple here there is a
да вот сри очень простой вот есть там
test so far called whose
тест пока называется чей
Crimea test of whom so far that is your test Yes
Крым тест кого пока то есть ваш тест Да
mine whose
мой чей
Crimea Crimeans about everything recorded you in
Крым крымчан о всё записали тебя в
statistics I just don't understand in
статистику Я вот просто не понимаю в
principle your essence Here is this can I do
принципе ваши суть Вот это кана вообще
n't understand at all you in principle you yourselves
не понимаю вы же в принципе сами вот
are starting this fire in from roulette very very much
этот огонь гаете в от рулетки очень
I I just think that
очень разжигают я Я просто считаю что
the fire should burn not only on this
огонь должен гореть не только по эту
side of the borders But also on that side for example
сторону границ А ещё и по ту например
here ZSU is starting a fire in Belgorod do
вот зсу разжигает огонь в Белгороде вот
you like it how do you feel about it what is it well
вам нравится это как вы к этому
in Belgorod they say in nom
это ну наме в Белгороде говорят ном
year that a person died just in one
годом че человека погибло просто в одном
Belgorod Maybe it's time to stop the war But
Белгороде Может пора остановить войну А
this is bad This is bad I don't know
это же плохо Это же плохо не знаю это
all this we don't know the whole truth
все мы всей правды не
we don't know the whole truth we don't know the
знаем мы же не знаем всей правды смыс не
meaning I mean we don't
знаем В смысле не
know Maybe they were bad people Maybe
знаем Может они плохие люди были Может
they were maybe these 24 were
это были может эти 24 были
what difference did it make they were people well how could it not be
какая разница это были люди ну как не
Maybe this can't be they Maybe they
так Может это не может они Может они
wanted
хотели
people Yes maybe it can't be you will talk to someone
людей Да может быть не может быть это вы
else
другому буде
here is not the Supreme Commander is clear here not everything is
гово тут не ВС однозначно тут не всё
clear we don't have all the
однозначно мы не имеем всей полноты
information  look there those who are at the top they know
информации смотри там тем кто наверху им
better for example Zaluzhny says about
виднее например говорит Залужный по
Belgorod that means he knows why we
Белгороду значи он знает ради чего мы
know with you
знаем с тобо
but there are people sitting there who know Yes here not
но там сидят люди которые шарят Да тут
everything is so clear you understand I don't
не всё так однозначно понимаешь понима
understand You don't
не понимаю Ты меня не понимаешь Не
understand me I don't understand I say it doesn't matter someone was these were
понимаю я говорю без разницы кто-то был
people Well so what they were Living
это были люди Ну и что это были Живые
people so and now they are Dead you say Well
люди так а теперь они Мёртвые говориш Ну
look for example there were
вот смотрите были например в Мариуполе
Living people in Mariupol Yes And these Belgorod
Живые люди Да И вот эти белгородские
people made them dead made
люди сделали их мёртвыми сделали
dead Mariupol Maybe these are these 24
мёртвыми Мариуполь Может это вот эти 24
who died in Belgorod They were just
которые погибли в Белгороде Они как раз
supporting the war It
поддерживали войну
seems to me that it was like that We don't
Мне кажется что так и было Мы же не
know the whole thing I think that I think that the
знаем всей Вот я думаю что я думаю что
shells that fly into the territory of
снаряды которые прилетают на территории
Belgorod they choose exactly
Белгорода они выбирают именно
and I don't
и я так не
think so Russia I understand Russia in Ukraine
считаю Россия я понимаю Россия в Украине
kills ordinary citizens I don't meddle in
убивает граждан обычных я не лезу не в
I don't meddle in politics I I I
на я не лезу в политику я
meddle in politics I will tell you as a politician
я я лезу в политику я тебе как политик
Yes in Belgorod Yes 24
расскажу Да в Белгороде Да погибли 24
Nazis died 24 in Belgorod  died It's
нациста 24 в Белгороде погибло Это же
good that a
хорошо что
Nazi This is against Look Putin said he
нацист Это прот смотри Путин сказал
will carry out a denazification act This was
проведёт акт денацификация Вот это был
carried out by the ZSU carried out a denazification act of the
проведён зсу провело акт денацификация
Belgorod People's
Белгородской народной
Republic Yes I know yes I'm telling you I don't know
Республики Да я знаю да я я тебе как
at all I'm saying
говорю я не сю вообще я говорю погибли
people died Well we don't know look we don't know
люди Ну мы не знаем смотри мы не знаем А
Maybe it was people You see Maybe it was
может это люди были Понимаешь Может это
killed we don't know the whole Truth You
уби были мы не знаем всей Правды Ты
know these people twenty-four Well
знаешь этих людей двадцати четырёх Ну
you now you now just
вот ты сейчас ты сейчас же просто
I don't want to argue what I'm not saying I'm
вот я не хочу спорить что не говорю я
telling you
тебе говорю погибли
people died is it bad or good I'm asking you this
люди это плохо или хорошо я тебя вот это
if people died in Ukraine It's
спрашиваю если в Украине погибли Это
bad if people died in Ukraine it's
плохо если в Украине погибли люди это
bad I mean if it's bad in Ukraine
плохо В смысле если в Украине это плохо
Of course if people died in Ukraine It's
Конечно если в Украине люди погибли Это
bad It's a base Well and in Belgorod Well that's it
плохо Это ж база Ну а в Белгороде Ну это
and if in any other country then it's
то а если в любой другой стране то это
ho in the USA - It's bad In France it's
хо в США - Это плохо Во Франции это
bad in Poland It's bad And in Russia
плохо в Польше Это плохо А в России Тут
Not everything is clear here look not everything is
не всё однозначно смотри тут не всё
clear here we don't know the whole truth here we
однозначно мы всей правды не знаем тут
need to figure it out Depending on which side you
надо разобраться Смотря с какой стороны
look at it from Well why is it funny funny bra
посмотреть Ну почему смешно смешной бра
We don't know the whole Truth Well look
Мы же не знаем всей Правды Ну смотри
Maybe it was the Nazis  what difference does it make
Может это нацисты были какая разница с
which country again look well you you
какой страны ещё раз смотри ну ты ты
agree look you agree that there is never
согла смотри ты согласен что никогда нет
100% certainty I
100% однозначности
agree well in this in this C No well how
согласен ну в этой в этой Си Не ну как
Wait stop stop no never never
Подожди стоп стоп не никогда никогда не
happens like certainty never
бывает типа однозначности никогда не
happens we don't know the whole truth we don't
бывает мы всей правды не знаем мы не
know the whole Truth You're from I don't
знаем всей Правды Ты с какого го не
know what difference does it make I yes in general you see
зна какая разница Я да вообще с видишь
you're not from Belgorod and I'm not from Belgorod
ты же не с Белгорода и я не с Белгорода
we don't know the whole Truth you understand we don't
мы не знаем всей Правды понимаешь мы не
know the Truth if for example in America or
знаем Правды если например в Америке или
in France or in Poland yes someone
во Франции или в Польше да кто-то бы
died it would be very sad in
один погиб это было бы очень печально в
Ukraine it's sad Yeah well in Belgrade we ca
Украине это печально Да ну в Белграде мы
n't know we can't be 100%
не можем знать мы не можем на 100% быть
sure you can be 100% sure no
уверен ты можешь на 100% быть уверен нет
and I No we don't know we don't know the whole
и я Нет мы не знаем мы не знаем всей
Truth understand all this those who
Правды пойми это всё вот те кто там
sit there at the top Putin and Zelensky they
сидят наверху Путин и Зеленский они
know the truth Yes they know we then maybe
знают правду Да они знают мы потом может
someday we will find out this truth yes But now
когда-то узнаем эту правду да Но сейчас
they know you understand we have information we are
они знают ты понима владеем информа мы
small di's who don't have
маленькие ди которые не владеют
information they
информацией они
have I mean they  I own the
владеют В смысле они владею
transformation Well Putin look Putin and
трансформацией Ну Путин смотри Путин и
Zelensky know why people died in
Зеленский знают почему погибли люди в
Belgorod They understand we don't understand that
Белгороде Они понимают мы не понимаем
means Well look if if Putin doesn't
значит Ну смотри если если Путин это не
stop it means
останавливает значит это для чего-то
Russia needs it for something True Putin could have
нужно России правда ведь Путин мог бы
stopped the war once and people in
раз и остановить войну и люди в
Belgorod wouldn't die that means Putin already knows
Белгороде не погибали то есть Путин уже
better Look Putin has been bombing Ukraine for 2 years now I'll say
виднее смотри Путин уже 2 года я скажу
no you can't [ __ ] Wait a minute I'll come to an agreement
не нельзя сри Подожди минут я договорюсь
Look Putin has been bombing Ukraine for 2 years and
смотри Путин 2 года так бомбит Украину а
Ukraine is bombing Belgorod yes that means Putin has been doing it for a
Украина бомбит Белгород да то есть Путин
long time If he felt sorry for the people in
давно если бы ему жалко было людей в
Belgorod Yes he would have stopped the war a long time ago
Белгороде Да он бы давно остановил войну
But Putin means he knows something He understands
но Путин значит что-то знает он понимает
that these people who are dying in
что эти люди которые погибают в
Belgorod they are dying for something Come on
Белгороде они за что-то погибают Давай
tell me I'm telling you people died
говори я тебе говорю погибли люди ещё
again I repeat to you people died how And
раз я тебя повторяю погибли люди как А
you
ты мне
attribute presidents to me yes Well look well
приписывает президентов да Ну смотри ну
since Tin doesn't stop the death of people in
раз тин не останавливает гибель людей
Belgorod there is some sense in
Белгороде знат есть какой-то смысл в
this Wait and why let's say
этом й Подожди а почему допустим
Vladimir Zelensky didn't stop Putin
Владимир Зеленский не Остана так Путин
started the war if Putin is withdrawing his
начал войну если Путин забирает свои
troops from Ukraine  and that's it in Belgorod no
войска из Украины и всё в Белгороде
one dies Well Putin look Putin
никто не погибает Ну Путин смотри Путин
look Putin Just can stop the
смотри Путин Просто может остановить
killing of people in Belgorod just
убийство людей в Белгороде просто
takes troops from Ukraine and no one
забирает войска из Украины и никто в
dies in Belgorod the next day
Белгороде не умирает на следующий день
not Zelen
не Зелен не
can't Zen said We look No while
может Зен сказали Мы смотри Нет пока
Russian troops are on our territory they
войска российски на нашей территории нас
bomb us according to Bel and that's what they say Zelensky won't
бомбят по бел так и говорят Зеленский не
stop No well Putin this is his
остановит Не ну Путин это его
Belgorod
белгородски
ens Belgorod Because these are not our
енс Белгород Потому что это не наши
citizens eld these are citizens of the Russian
граждане елд это Граждане Российской
Federation who should worry about them
Федерации кто за них должен переживать
Why doesn't the president of the Russian Federation
Поче президент россий Федерации не
worry about Belgorod for the residents of
переживает за Белгород за жителей
Belgorod why won't he stop Putin
Белгорода почему он не остановит Путин
won't say look I care about every
не скажет смотрите Мне важна каждая
life Belgorod let's go Donbass Crimea In short
жизнь Белгород пошли Донбасс Крым Короче
I want Belgorod to live peacefully he
я хочу чтобы Белгород жил мирно он не
can't because that means he knows something
может потому что значит что-то он знает
here not everything is clear we don't understand the Armed Forces
тут не всё однозначно мы не понимаем ВС
we don't know the whole Truth you don't know the
мы не знаем всей Правды ты не знаешь
whole Truth Why Putin Tiny is
всей Правды Для чего Путин Тини
needed this about
нужна это про
dying caption on y Instagram I don't
погибают пидпись на й Instagram Я не
know why this is for what else tob there
знаю для чого це тоб для чого ще тоб там
look at this face  But for you it's
дивитись на оцей й фейс Але для тебе це
one two or three clicks But you try
один два або три клика Але ты тримае
me and I'll be in you there are a bunch of fouls and
мене и я буду ти в мене там Купа фолов и
I'll be in a cool mood to do but a
в мене буде класний настр щоб робити но
round video letter on y instag until Andriy
кру видео пись на й instag пок Андрий
then Come on
отак
I'm waiting for you
Давай я тебя чекаю